cer.eu 2019-05-30

# Privacy policy | Centre for European Reform

**Centre for European Reform privacy policy**

The Centre for European Reform protects and respects the data privacy of all our contacts. Our privacy policy explains how we collect personal information via our website. It also explains how we use our contacts’ information, when and why we may disclose it to others and how we keep it secure.

We may change this policy from time to time. By using our website you agree to be bound by this policy.

Any questions regarding this policy should be sent by email to kate@cer.eu or in writing to Kate Mullineux, Centre for European Reform, 14 Great College Street, London, SW1P 3RX. Alternatively, you can telephone +44 (0) 207 233 1199.

The Centre for European Reform is an independent, private, not-for-profit organisation, established in 1996 with the mission to make the European Union work better and strengthen its role in the world. The Centre for European Reform is a company limited by guarantee (no. 03484649). The registered address is 14 Great College Street, London, SW1P 3RX.

We obtain information about you when you use our website, for example, when you contact us about our events, or if you sign up to receive our publications or multimedia mailings.

The personal information we collect might include your name, address, email address, IP address, and information regarding which pages are accessed.

Your information may be used to:

  * process events registrations that you have submitted
  * fulfil contractual obligations if we have them with you
  * send you communications which you have requested or which may be of interest to you. These may include publications, podcasts, information about forthcoming events and other information related to our work
  * process job applications

We review how long we hold your personal information regularly. We must hold some types of information to fulfil our statutory obligations. We will hold your personal information on our systems for only as long as is necessary for the relevant activity.Sharing information

We will not share your information with third parties.

If we would like to share your information with third parties in relation to your attendance at a particular event you will be explicitly informed when registering for the event and your details would only be provided on an explicit opt-in basis.

We may also pass your information to other third-party service providers, agents and subcontractors for the purposes of completing tasks and providing services to you on our behalf. However, when we use third-party service providers, we disclose only the personal information that is necessary to deliver the service.

 **Your choices  
** You have a choice about whether or not you wish to receive information from us. If you do not want to receive communications from us about our work and our events then you can opt out by using the link within any of the emails that we send you.

You can also change your preferences at any time by contacting us by email: mailing@cer.eu or telephone on +44 (0) 207 233 1199.

 **Updating your information  
** The accuracy of your information is important to us. If you change email address, or any of the other information we hold is inaccurate or out of date, please email us at [mailing@cer.eu](mailto:mailing@cer.eu), or write to us at Kate Mullineux, Centre for European Reform, 14 Great College Street, London, SW1P 3RX. Alternatively, you can telephone +44 (0) 207 233 1199.

 **Security precautions  
** Non-sensitive details (your email address etc) are transmitted normally over the internet, and this can never be guaranteed to be 100 per cent secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your information, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

 **Use of 'cookies'  
** Like many other websites, the Centre for European Reform website uses cookies. A cookie is a small text file passed to your computer, mobile phone or other device, through your web browser, so the website remembers who you are when you return.

The Centre for European Reform uses Google Analytics to track how this website is used. Google Analytics uses cookies to help gather statistics on how people use websites. For example, which country the user is from, and which pages are visited while on the website. We use this information to look at how our website is being used so we can assess how well it is working and to help us make decisions about how to improve it.

Cookies may also be used by some parts of the site where we utilise third-party services, such as YouTube and Vimeo for video content and SoundCloud for audio content.

If you do not wish to have cookies stored on your computer you can easily change your web browser to refuse them, or to let you know when you get a new cookie. You need to refer to your internet browser's instructions by clicking on the 'Help' menu. Refusing cookies, however, can restrict your use of our website.

 **Links to other websites**

Our website may contain links to other websites run by other organisations. This privacy policy applies only to our website‚ so we encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit. We cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of other sites even if you access them using links from our website.

In addition, if you linked to our website from a third-party site, we cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of the owners and operators of that third-party site and recommend that you check the policy of that third party site.

 **Transferring your information outside of Europe**

Some of the information which you provide to us may be transferred to countries outside the European Union. By way of example, some Centre for European Reform events are held in countries outside of the EU. These countries may not have similar data protection laws to the UK. By submitting your personal data, you are agreeing to this transfer.

If you use our services while you are outside the EU, your information may be transferred outside the EU in order to provide you with those services.

 **Review of this policy**

We keep this policy under regular review. This policy was last updated in March 2019.
